Finding Aid for the Lacy Jr, Charles Lockert, Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Lockert, Charles Lacy, Jr. Papers
2002
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0263
5.46 linear feet
LOCKERT, (Charles) Lacy (Jr.) 1SSS-1974
PERSONAL: Born May 18. IS88. inCUrksviUe.Tcnn.; km of Charles Lacy (a druggist) and Nannie (Smith) Lockart. Education: Southwestern Presbyterian University, A.B., 1907, A.M., 1909; Princeton University, Ph.D.. 1916.
CAREER: Kenyon College, Gambier, Ohio, assistant professor of English. 1916-25; retired early in order to study and write. Member: Modern Language Association of America, Sierra Club.
WRITINGS—Translator and author of critical material, except as noted: (Author of commentary) Massinfer and Field, The Fatal Dowry. New Era Press, 1918; (contrftwtor) H. Craig, editor. Essays in Dramatic Literature: The Par- rott Presentation Volume, Princeton University Press, 1935; Dante Alighieri, The Inferno, Princeton University Press. 1936; Jean Baptiste Racine, Best Plays, Princeton University Press, 1936; Pierre Comeille, Chief Plays. Princeton University Press, 1952, 2nd edition, 1957; (editor) Orville Ernest Watson, Selected Sermons. Kenyon College, 1955; The Chief Rivals of Corneille and Racine, Vanderbilt University Press, 1956; (author) Studies in French-classical Tragedy, Vanderbilt University Press, 1958; Racine, Mid- career Tragedies, Princeton University Press, 1958; Corneille, Moot Plays. Vanderbilt University Press, 1959; More Plays by Rivals of Corneille and Racine, Vanderbilt University Press, 1968. Contributor to Sewanee Review, North American Review, and other journals.
AVOCATIONAL INTERESTS: Great natural scenery, and photographing it; history of American intercollegiate football; Wagnerian opera.t
Chronology
1888 Born in Clarksville, Tennessee; only child.
1903-1909 A.B. and A.M. at Southwestern Presbyterian University at Clarksville. (Now Southwestern at Memphis)
1908 Correspondence with Nelle Ramsay begins.
1909 Enters Princeton University.
1912 Mother dies; family home broken up and Lockerts move to Nashville, Lacy suffers nervous breakdown which interrupts his doctoral studies at Princeton; treatment was in Nashville.
1915 Returns to Princeton in January. Nelle Ramsay dies in California in June.
1916 Completes Ph.D. at Princeton. Dissertation under direction of Thomas Marc Parrott. Assistant Professor of English, Kenyon College. Meets Philip Timberlake, who was then a senior ar Kenyon.
1917 Exempted from military service for poor health.
1918 Publishes dissertation. The Fatal Dowry by Philip Massinger and Nathaniel Field by Charles Lacy Lockert, Jr.) Lancaster, Pa: The New Era Printing Company.
1919 Articles: "Marston, Webster and the Decline of Elizabethan Drama," Sewanee Review, January. "Henryk Sienkiewicz," Sewanee Review, July.
1920 Article: "A Scene in 'The Fatal Dowry*," Modern Language Notes, May.
1921 Began Correspondence with Charte Kelsey Gaines with letter of appreciation for the novel, Gorgo, on May 12.
1922 Article: ••Some of Mr. Galsworthy's heroines," North American Review, February. Phi Beta Kappa Lecture at St. Lawrence University, Canton, N.Y. May 12. The Lecture, "World Drama and World Dramatists," was published in pamphlet form, by Commercial Advertiser Press, Canton, N.I. Thanksgiving Visit wi,th the C.K. Gaines family.
1922-1923 Chairman of the Gorgo essay contest for undergraduates sponsored by Kenyon College.
1925 (26?) Leaves Kenyon College and retires to write (in Nashville). Succeeded in his position at Kenyon by Philip Timberlake.
1931 Published first translation. The Inferno of Dante • Princeton University Press.
1935 Article: "The Greatest of Elizabethan Melodramas," Essays in Dramatic Literature: the Parrott Presentation Volume, Princeton University Press.
1935-1936 Thomas Marc Parrott is visiting professor at Vanderbilt. Acquaintance renewed, probably basis for correspondence in this collection.
1936 Published first of French translations: The Best Plays of Racine, Princeton University Press.
1938-1942 Louise Allen suffers major breakdown, described sis melancholia or manic depression in Lacy's letters. Indications are that she had experienced earlier breakdown in 1916.
1939 Article: "Racine's Berenice," Romanic Review, February.
1940 (4l) Charles Lacy Lockert, Sr. dies. Born December 19, 1855, died at age 85.
1944 Charles Kelsey Gaines dies. Correspondence with Clarence Hurd Gaines begins.
1946-1947 Louise Allen suffers setback; electro-shock treatments and extended hospitalization necessary.
1952 Publishes second book of French translations: Chief Plays of Cornellle« Princeton University Press.
1955 Lacy Lockert edits volume of sermons of Canon Watson of Kenyon College. (Orville Ernest Watson, 1857-1951). Selected Sermons of Orville E. Watson. Gambier; Kenyon College, tPrinted by Parthenon Press, Nashville)
1956 Publishes third book of translations: Chief Rivals of Corncille and Racine. Vanderbilt University Press.
1957 Piiilip Timberlake dies.
1958 Pu.bliah.ea fourth book of translations and a book of criticism: Racinels Mid-Career Tragedies, Princeton University Press. Studies in French-Classical Tragedy, Vanderbilt University Press.
1959 Publishes fifth book of translations: Moot Plays of Corneille, Vanderbilt University Press. Purchases memorial tablet for Nelle Ramsay (1887-1915)
1960 Thomas Marc Parrott dies.
1962 Edits and publishes novel by Charles Kelsey Gaines which was originally written in 1921: Gaines, Charles Kelsey Angel's Diary, Canton, N.Y,: St. Lawrence University TPrinted for St. Lawrence at Parthenon Press, Nashville.)
1968 Publishes sixth book of French translations: More Plays by Rivals of Corneille and Racine, Vanderbilt University Press.
1969 (?) Married Annie Louise Allen 197 Died in Nashville on April 21.
All information in this chronology is based on the correspondence of Lacy Lockert and from publications of his which are either available in reprint or in the collections of JUL. Some of the information in the chronology attempts to make the correspondence more useful by listing events in the lives of people close to Lacy Lockert.
- Correspondence - Incoming. 1908-1970. —- 180 letters, most holograph, many typed. I Ir 13 postcards, 1 Christmas card, 2 telegrasB and 1 invitation. Arranged alphabetically according to sender. Folders 1-10. (Folder 1)
- Typescript of incoming correspondence from Nelle Ramsay, 1908-1915. All letters and postcards from this collection are included but some paragraphs sire deleted. There are also typescripts of some of Lacy Lockert*s replies and his comments on the correspondence in this typescript. Folder 11. (Folder 1)
- Photographs., a) Nelle Ramsay, c. 1910 b) Lacy Lockert, boxing photo, probably taken while at Princeton. c) Charles Kelsey Gaines and Lacy Lockert, Canton, N.Y., 1922. (Two copies) d) Frank E. Miller, III, c. WW II. Folder 12 (Folder 1)
- Draft Records WW I. Certificate of Discharge, Doctor's certificate, War Department notices, and clipping from The Nashville Tennessean, July 15, 1917. Folder 13- (Folder 1)
- Football Statistics and Inventions. A sampling of all-time great teams selected by the Lockert method. Folder l1*. (Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Clippings. Includes football clippings and articles about friends: Mrs. Charles Kelsey Gaines, Frank Miller, Jr., Philip Timberlake, and Mrs. Mebane Ramsay. Folder 15. (Folder 1)
- Financial Papers: Miscellaneous bank state ments and receipts; stock announcements and stockholder's reports; Letter of bequest to Vanderbilt University, accepted by O.C. Car- michael, July 16, 1943 (Xerox copy); rough draft of article in Lacy Lockert's will concerning publication of Gorgo; order and receipt for memorial tablet for Nelle Ramsay, September 2, 1959* Folder 17. (Folder 1)
- Correspondence - Outgoing. 1908-1965. 139 letters, primarily holograph, with some typescripts, especially to publishers. Carbon copies and photo copies are few. Arranged chronologically. Folders 1-7. (Folder 2)
- Correspondence - Outgoing. 1943-1957. (Folder 2)
- letters to Thomas Marc Parrott. All of these letters are holograph and were not dated by Lacy Lockert. Approximate dates were assigned on the basis of internal evidence. Folder 8. (Two other letters to Mr. Parrott which could not be separated from other correspondence may be found in Folders 5 and 6) (Folder 2)
- Political opinions. Essays on Eleanor Roosevelt (Two copies, plus one fragment), Franklin Roosevelt and Harry Truman (One copy), and integration (fragment). These essays appear to be a part of the outgoing correspondence, possibly to either Mebane Ramsay or Philip Timberlake. There is also a reprint of General Douglas MacArthur's address to Congress, April 15, 1951* Folder 9. (Folder 2)
- Page Proofs of The Best Plays of Racine. Folder 10. (Folder 2)
- An Angel's Diary, Charles Kelsey Gaines. Thermofax copy of manuscript. Folder 11. (Folder 2)
- An Angel's Diary, galley proofs. Folder 12. (Folder 2)
- An Ansel's Diary, page proofs. Lacy Lockert*s introduction gives biographical material about Charles Kelsey Gaines. Folder 13. (Folder 2)
- Phi Beta Kappa Address, May 12, 1922, St. Lawrence University. Program and newspaper clippings from Canton, N.Y. area. Folder 1. (Folder 3)
- Gorgo Essay Contest. Clippings from April, 1922 from Canton, N.Y. area newspapers. Folder 2. (Folder 3)
- Gorgo vocabulary. Alphabetical study list x)f terms from Gorgo; no stated purpose for use of this list. Folder 3. (Folder 3)
- Course plans. Shakespeare 12*t, mimeographed two-page outline, Golograph of prospective seminar in French Classical Drama. Folder 4. (Folder 3)
- Spyglass, July 13, 1927. Bookpage from The Nashville Tennessean. Includes review of John Jay Chapman's Dante by Lacy Lockert. Folder 5. (Folder 3)
- Reviews:. The Best Plays of Racine. Clippings from The Nashville Banner and The Nashville Tennessean, January 10, 1937. Typescript copies of reviews appearing in Notes and Queries, Modern Language Notes, The Chattanooga News, Chattanooga Times, The Brooklyn Teacher, Vancouver Sun. Folder 6. (Folder 3)
- Reviews of other Lockert publications. April 8, 1922, America, on "Some of Mr. Galsworthy's heroines." (Folder 3)
- Unidentified review of Dante's Inferno. December 1932, New Republic, The Chief Plays of Corneille. July 10, 1953, TLS, The Chief Plays of Corneille. (Folder 3)
- Summer, 1953, 17th Century News, The Chief Plays of Corneille. (Folder 3)
- January 6, 1957, Nashville Tennessean, The Chief Rivals of Corneille and Racine. September 1959« The Book Exchange, Studies in French-Classical Tragedy. Holograph copy of reviews in The Christian Century, January 7, 1953; Morning Telegraph, N.Y., August 29, 1952; TLS, September 11, 1959. (Folder 3)
- Typescript of selected quotations from reviews for brochure on The Chief Plays of Corneille. Folder 7. (Folder 3)
- Dust Wrappers, Vanderbilt University Press. Hoot Plays of Corneille, The Chief Rivals of Corneille and Racine, Studies in French-Classical Tragedy. Folder 8. (Folder 3)
- Publishers' Memoe. Advertising flyers and letters from Princeton University Press and Vanderbilt University Press on Lockert's works. Also brochures from Richard R. Smith Publishing and Collection des Classiques Garniers. Folder 9. (Folder 3)
- Reprints of Gacy Lockert Articles., a) "Marston, Webster and the Decline of Elizabethan Drama," Sewanee Review, January 1919* b) "ttenryk Sienkiewicz," Sewanee Review, July 1919* c) *'A Scene in 'The Fatal Dowry'," MLN, May 1920. d) "World Drama and World Dramatists," 1922. (Phi Beta Kappa Lecture at St. Lawrence) e) "The Greatest of Elizabethan welodramas." Essays in Dramatic Literature; The Parrott Presentation Volume. Princeton University Press, 1935. f) "Racine's Berenice," Romanic Review, February, 1939. Folder 10. (Folder 3)
- Scholarly Reprint. Hunter Kellenberger, "Voltaire's Treatment of the Miracle of Christ's Temptation in the Wilderness," MLN, January 1936. Autographed. Folder 11. (Folder 3)
- Ms. "Mr. Galsworthy'and His Unworthy Gals. Original, unabridged version. (Shortened version published as "Some of Mr. Galsworthy's Geroines," North American Review, February, 1922.) Folder 12. (Folder 3)
- Notes for "The Greatest of Elizabethan Melo dramas." (CT. Folder 3-10) Folder 13. (Folder 3)
- Ms. "Beaumont's Hand in Four Plays in One." Folder 14 (Folder 3)
- Notes for Beaumont manuscript. Folder 15. (Folder 3)
- Ms. "William Archer and Elizabethan and Modern Drama." Pencil Comments may be by Thomas Marc Parrott, who read this manuscript. Folder 16. (Folder 3)
- Ms. "An Imitation by Corneille of Racine." Folder 17. (Folder 3)
- PMLA manuscript and correspondence on the sources of Andromaque. A set of articles intended for the Comment and Criticism department in 1937-1938 but never published. Folder 18. (Folder 3)
- Ms. The Death of Hector; a transcript of Homer, Iliad XXII~ typescript and holograph. Folder 19. (Folder 3)
- Essay. Again on Translating Homer. Folder 20. (Folder 3)
- Notecards on Aeschylus translations. (Manuscript of Aeschylus translations sent to Grinceton University Press. Cf. Holograph of letter to Princeton University Press, 12 March 1953, Folder 2-M. Folder 21. (Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous notes and fragments. Notes from readings and incomplete essays on dramatic theory, translations, the historical novel and other topics. Folder 22. (Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous unpublished manuscripts., a) Is the Poet Inspired? b) The Methods of Literary Criticism. c) A Summary of Wordsworth's Criticism of Poetry. (a,b,c, may be class lectures from Kenyon) d) Poem. "Bishop Chase Leaves Gambier" e) My Fling at Philosophy. f) Concerning Park Roads and Attractions. Folder 23. (Folder 3)
- Ms. "The Adventure of The Brothers Karamazov: A. Teile of Sherlock Holmes." An original short story in which Holmes solves the murder case in Dostoyevsky's novel. Folder 2b (Folder 3)
- Fragment of unfinished historical novel on Xenophon. Folder 25. (Folder 3)
- Clamence Housman: "The Werewolf". Typescript marked p.105 to conclusion. This may be a Lacy Lockert revision as it uses Allan Thorne as the hero, the same figure used in Lockert's The True End of the Ring. Folder 26. (Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous writings of others. (Typescripts), a) Song from "The Julius Caesar Murder Case" by Will Irwin. b) From Modern Dramatists by Ashley Dukesl (London, 191lTT c) From The Fugitive Group by Louise Cowan (LSU Press, 1959). Folder 27. (Folder 3)
- c) de Pharr. Mimeographed copies of ms. a) A Project for the Translation into English of the Entire Body of Roman Law: Preliminary Statement. 1943. b) The Final Agony of the Roman Empire in the West. (Presidential address at the Classical Association of the Middle West and South, April 6-8, 1944.) Folder 28. (Folder 3)
- The True End of the Ring, Fragment of the holograph manuscript. Folder 1. (Folder 4)
- Tolkien. Volume III. Revision, Chapters 10-13. First Draft. Folder 2. (Folder 4)
- Tolkien. Book VI. Chapters 1-9. Also re-vised chronology. First Draft. Folders 3-7. (Folder 4)
- Tolkien. Book VI. Work Sheets. Folder 8. (Folder 4)
- True End of the Ring. Lockert's revision of the Ring Trilogy in its final manuscript form, introducing his hero, Allan Thorne. Folders 9-16. (Folder 4)
- (Cf. Five-page copy of letter to Alida Sima Malkus, 17 November 1965 (Folder 2-7) for a description of Lacy Lockert's purpose and his ideas on rewriting the end of the Ring Trilogy.) (Folder 4)
- "The Return of Allan Thorne". A separate short story involving another journey to Tolkien's fantasy world by the hero invented by Lockert. Folder 1. (Folder 5)
- Nelle Ramsay Manuscripts. Folders 2-10. All of these unpublished writings of Ellen (Nelle) Ramsay, 1888-1915» were sent by her brother, Frank Ramsay, to Lacy Lockert after her sudden death in California. Frank Ramsay made some attempt at ordering and organizing the materials by content but no dating or editing of these materials was ever done. A brief comparison of the subject matter of these manuscripts with correspondence with members of the Ramsay family, Nelle, Frank and webane, would suggest that all of these manuscripts were written between 1909-1915. Apparently Lacy Lockert evaluated them in hopes of publishing some of them posthumously, but decided to save them for personal reasons only. A summary of the contents follows: 5 Proposed Novel: One Turn of the Wheel. Folder 2. (Folder 5)
- (Nelle Ramsay manuscripts continued) (Folder 5)
- One-Act Play: In the Blood. First Draft. Folder 3. (Folder 5)
- Poem Sequence. Folder 4. (Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous unfinished poems. Auto biographical content. Folder 5* (Folder 5)
- Unfinished short stories. Nine fragments, most untitled. Folder 6. (Folder 5)
- Untitled short story. Part of conclusion seems missing. Subject: Edna Yarrow at Hyde Park Academy, an autobiographical parallel to one of Nelle's teaching experiences. Folder 7* (Folder 5)
- Untitled short story. Subject: Death of Tam. Some autobiographical reference to Lacy Lockerts illness in 1912 may be source of this material. Folder 8. (Folder 5)
- Essays. All autobiographical and some bear the character of attempts at poemes en prose.. Folder 9. (Folder 5)
- Outgoing Correspondence. All of this undated. Correspondents include Marjory Curry, Mary Gavin, and Jean. Some of these were written under great stress and possibly were never mailed. Mary Gavin's letters, however, were sent to Frank after Nelle's death. Folder 10. (Folder 5)
- Manuscript Copy #1 of BY THE WILL OF APOLLO, by Charles Kelsey Gaines. Formerly titled In the Silence of the Gods, this manuscript has been edited and shortened by Lacy Lockert. Container also includes one file folder of pages excised from this copy. (Folder 6)
- Manuscript copy #2 of BY THE WILL OF APOLLO, by Charles Kelsey Gaines. This version is the full-length copy sent to Lacy Lockert. Perhaps C.K. Gaines himself had attempted to shorten the work as there Eire some pages in one folder which seem to be excised pages from this version. (Folder 7)
- Selected Sermons of Canon Orville E. Watson: Work sheets on the introduction and table of contents of this edition of sermons published by Kenyon College after Canon Watson's death. Folder 1. (Folder 8)
- List of sermons for projected second volume of sermons by Canon 0. E. Watson. No evidence that •Gacy Lockert pursued very actively the publication of this second volume. Folder 2. (Folder 8)
- Manuscript of Other Sermons of Canon Watson. (Unpublished edition75 (Folder 8)
- N.B. All folders in Container 9 are manuscript materials for chapters in the following books: The Best Plays of Racine(Princeton, 1936); The Chief Plays of Corneille (Princeton, 1952); Chief Rivals of Corneille and Racine (Vanderbilt, 1956]"; and The Mid-Career Tragedies of Racine ( Princeton, 195877" (Folder 9)
- Notes and corrections for The Best Plays of Racine, 1936. Miscellaneous notes, rough drafts and lists of manuscript corrections. Folder 1. (Cf. Folder 2-10 for page proofs.) (Folder 9)
- Drafts and revisions of Phi&dre translation and introductory essay, typescript and holograph. Folder 2. (Folder 9)
- Notes, revisions and corrections for The Chief Plays of Corneille, 1952. holograph and typescript of introduction; pages of manuscript corrections, miscellaneous notes. Folder 3. (Folder 9)
- Holograph of translation of Corneille: The Cid. Folder 4. (Folder 9)
- Holograph of translation of Corneille: Horace. Folder 5. (Folder 9)
- Holograph of translation of Corneille: Cinna. Folder 6. (Folder 9)
- Holograph of translation of Corneille: Polyeucte. Folder 7. (Folder 9)
- Holograph of translation of Corneille: Njcomedes. Folder 8. (Folder 9)
- Title pages and dedication: The Chief Rivals of Corneille and Racine, 1956. Folder 9. (Folder 9)
- Holograph of translation of Jean de Gairet: Sophonisbe. Folder. 10. (Folder 9)
- Notes and introduction to Ia Gariamne by Tristan 1'Hermite. Holograph and typescript. Folder 11. (Folder 9)
- Notes and revisions for ffgevole by Pierre Du liyer. (Folder 9)
- olograph and typescript™ Folder 12. (Folder 9)
- Notes and incomplete translation of Venceslas by Jean Rotrou. Holograph. Folder 13. (Folder 9)
- Incomplete holograph of translation of Laodice by 'J-'homas Corneille. Folder Ik. (Folder 9)
- Holograph of translation of Thomas Corneille: The Count of Essex. Folder 15. (Folder 9)
- Holograph of translation of Jean-Galbert Campistron: Andronic. Folder 16. (Folder 9)
- Typescript of translation of Antoine de la Fosse: Manlius Capitolinus. Folder 17. (Folder 9)
- Holograph of translation of Antoine de la Fosse: Manlius Capitolinus. Folder 18. (Folder 9)
- Holograph of translation and notes for Rhadamiste et Zenoble. Folder 19. (Folder 9)
- Holograph of translation of Voltaire: ZaSre. Folder 20. (Folder 9)
- Notes for Racine's Mid-Career Tragedies, 1958. Ba.jazet and Mithridate, notes and revisions. Holograph and typescript. Folder 21. (Folder 9)
- Notes and revisions for translation of Racine: Mithridate. Holograph and typescript. Folder 22. (Folder 9)
- Notes for Racine: Iphigenie. Holograph and typescript. Folder 23• (Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous notes on Racine. Unidentified work sheets. Holograph and typescript. Folder 2*t. (Folder 9)
- Commentary on translations. Notes from Louise fierce oh Venceslae, Comte d'Essex, and one unidentified text. Folder 25. (Folder 9)
- N.B. All folders in Container 10 are manuscript materials for Studies in French Classical Tragedy, Vanderbilt, 1958. (Folder 10)
- First draft and notes for Introduction to Studies in French Classical Tragedy, Holograph and typescript. Folder 1. (Folder 10)
- Drafts and revisions for introduction, typescript. Folder 2. (Folder 10)
- "The Amazing Career of Pierre Corneille." Carbon of typescript manuscript. Folder 3« (Folder 10)
- "The Amazing Career of Pierre Corneille." Notes and revisions. Folder (Folder 10)
- Tristan l'Hermite: A French "Duchess of Malfi" ILa Mariane). Typescript. Folder 5« (Folder 10)
- "Du Ryer as a Writer of Tragedy." Typescript. Folder 6. (Folder 10)
- "Du Ryer as a Writer of Tragedy": notes and revisions, Golograph and typescript. Folder 7« (Folder 10)
- HCosroea: Rotrou's Best Play." Typescript. Folder 8. (Folder 10)
- "The Tragedies of Thomas Corneille." Type script. Folder 9. (Folder 10)
- "Quinault's Astrate." Typescript. Folder 10. (Folder 10)
- "Quinault's Astrate." Holograph fragment of rough draft. Folder 11. (Folder 10)
- "Racine's Apprenticeship." Typescript. Folder 12. (Folder 10)
- "Racine's Andromaque." Typescript. Folder 13. (Folder 10)
- "Racine's Britannicus." Typescript. Folder (Folder 10)
- "Racine's Berenice." Typescript. Folder 15. (Folder 10)
- Notes and revisions for"Racine's Berenice." Typescript. Folder 16. (Folder 10)
- "Racine's Bajazet." Typescript. Folder 17. (Folder 10)
- "Racine's Mithridate." Typescript. Folder 18. (Folder 10)
- Notes on Mithridate. Holograph. Folder 19. (Folder 10)
- "Racine's Iphigenie." Typescript. Folder 20. (Folder 10)
- "Racine's Phedre." Typescript. Folder 21. (Folder 10)
- "Racine's Athalie." Typescript. Folder 22. (Folder 10)
- "After Racine: Campistron." Typescript. Folder 22. (Folder 10)
- "After Racine: Campistron." Incomplete draft and notes. Typescript and holograph. Folder 24. (Folder 10)
- "Manlius Capitolinus." typescript. Folder 25. (Folder 10)
- "Neo-Classical Tragedy in the Eighteenth Century." Typescript. Folder 26. (Folder 10)
- "Neo-Classical Tragedy in the Eighteenth Century." Notes and revisions..Holograph and typescript fragment. Folder 27. (Folder 10)
- "Elizabethan and French-classical Drama." Typescript. Folder 28. (Folder 10)
- Notes for "Elizabethan and French-classical Drama." Holograph and typescript. Folder 29* (Folder 10)
- N.B. All folders in Container 11 are manu script materials fof Moot Plays of Corneille, Vanderbilt, 1959. (Folder 11)
- Introduction to Moot Plays of Corneille. Typescript carbon. Folder 1. (Folder 11)